《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我们有搜查令
We got a warrant
可以搜查他的办公室和里面的一切
to search his office and everything in it.
我不确定还有什么东西可看
I'm just not sure there's much more to see.
我们盯上你了
We're on to you.
死人进  怪物出
Dead people come here, and monsters come out.
首要规则
Rule number one:
照顾好首要人物
Look after number one.
别发疯  否则你会害死自己
Don't be crazy, or you're get yourself killed.
很高兴有人在乎我
It's nice to have someone who cares about me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为什么他们总是消失在那条走廊尽头
Why do they keep disappearing down that hallway?
天呐
Oh, my...
看看你父亲身边的那个人
Look at the man next to your father.
雨果·斯特兰奇  哲学家
Hugo Strange. "The Philosopher."
是朋友  是他信任的人
A friend. Someone he trusted.
这不公平
That's not fair.
这不对
That's not right.
你看新闻了吗
Have you seen the news?
哥谭有行尸吗
Walking zombies in Gotham?
有什么大惊小怪的
What's new?
维克多·弗莱斯和西奥·盖勒文去阿卡姆时
Victor Fries and Theo Galavan both went to Arkham
都是死人了  两个人都活了
as dead men. Both returned.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你朋友布莉姬特也是
So did your friend Bridget.
布莉姬特·派克
Bridgit Pike!
等等  他们把她送去阿卡姆了
Wait, they sent her to Arkham?
唯一能查清真相的办法
The only way we're ever going to find out what's really going on in there
就是我们自己闯进去
is if we break in ourselves.
但我要一个人去
But I go alone.
老天爷
Holy cow!
-法医男  -街头女
- Forensic guy? - Street trash girl?
斯特兰奇在哪
Where is Strange right now?
有个电梯
There's an elevator.
我会告诉你在哪
I'll tell you where it is.
别动
Freeze.
-布莉姬特  -我叫
- Bridgit? - My name's...
萤火虫
Firefly.
你越早站住别动
The sooner you stop moving,
这一切就能越早结束
the sooner this will be over.
多谢
Thanks.
还是不必了
No thanks.
你逃不出去的
You can't escape.
玩得开心  萤火虫
Enjoy yourself, Firefly.
你应该感到荣幸
You should feel honored.
你是火之女神的祭品
You are a sacrifice to the Goddess of Fire.
这是少数人才能得到的恩赐
It's a blessing few receive.
布莉姬特...
Man, Bridgit...
你脑子真是被搅和得不轻
someone sure scrambled your eggs.
仅供学习  禁止商用  更多影视
登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 小胖纸Amy   辰星晓Reginamoon   Silence   DustD
翻译 charcie   大K   小酸奶!   草草   后期 饿得慌
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
你迟到了  塞琳娜
You're late, Selina.
我都开始担心了
I was starting to get worried.
我没迟到  我来的恰是时候
I'm not late; I'm exactly where I'm supposed to be.
你看到塞琳娜了吗
Have you seen Selina?
没
No.
那么...
So...
你又做回富二代了  是吗
you're back to being a rich kid, huh?
你为什么这副表情
Why does your face look like that?
塞琳娜...
Selina...
她有麻烦了  是我的错
She's in trouble and it's my fault.
关于昨晚发生的事
Regarding last night's nocturnal activities,
自称阿泽瑞尔的犯罪嫌疑人
a suspect calling himself Azrael
独自一人对韦恩庄园发起了攻击
led a one-man assault upon Wayne Manor,
引发了一场争斗
whereupon an altercation
随后嫌疑人被
ensued in which said suspect was
未知的一人或多人炸死
blown up by a person or persons unknown.
所以他死了  还有什么问题吗
So he's dead. Any questions?
你能确认那个死亡天使阿泽瑞尔
Can you confirm that the man known as Azrael
就是名誉扫地的盖勒文市长吗
was in fact disgraced Mayor Galavan?
鉴于嫌疑人现在已经成了肉渣
Well, seeing as how the suspect is now meat dust,
要得到确切的鉴定结果很困难
a positive identification would be difficult.
你代理警监会做多久
How long are you Acting Captain?
直到有其他人想接手这份工作
Until, literally, the second someone else wants the job.
谁杀了盖勒文
Who killed Galavan?
你指哪次
Which time?
天呐  阿泽瑞尔  盖勒文
Man! Give me Azrael, Galavan,
不论他是谁  都比那群豺狼虎豹好对付
or whoever the hell he was, over those jackals any day.
你得逮捕雨果·斯特兰奇
You need to bring in Hugo Strange.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
以什么罪名呢
On what charge?
你什么时候开始顾及这些了
Since when do you care?
自从我成为哥谭市警局的代理警监
Since I became Acting Captain, the GCPD,
整个城市都在盯着我的一言一行
and the whole damn city's got me under a microscope.
而且我们走过这条路了
Besides which, we've been down this road.
斯特兰奇很精明
Strange is smart.
他肯定已经掩蔽了罪证
He'll have covered his tracks.
我们如果不知道要找什么
It's pointless going into Arkham
去阿卡姆就毫无意义
unless we know what we're looking for.
我们只有进去了才知道要找什么
We can't get that unless we go in there.
我明白你的意思  兄弟
I hear you, brother,
但我也没办法
but my hands are tied.
是吗  我能想办法
Yeah? Well, mine aren't.
那就好好想吧  那可是我没有的福分
Well, enjoy it, 'cause that's a luxury I don't have.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
我就希望你在这里
I was hoping you'd be here.
布鲁斯  你不能再叫我警探了
Bruce, you've got to stop calling me detective.
怎么了
What is it?
塞琳娜
Selina.
雨果·斯特兰奇抓走了塞琳娜
Hugo Strange has Selina.
关于昨晚发生的事
Regarding last night's nocturnal activities,
自称阿泽瑞尔的犯罪嫌疑人
the suspect, calling himself Azrael...
独自一人对韦恩庄园发起了攻击
lead a one-man assault upon Wayne Manor...
引发了一场争斗
whereupon an altercation ensued, upon which...
喂
Yes?
斯特兰奇失控了
Strange is losing control.
我们得召集法庭
We need to gather the court.
遵命  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
哥谭
第二季  第二十一集
有心跳了
We have a heartbeat.
他正在苏醒
He's waking up.
看着我
Look at me.
早上好啊  孩子
Good morning, son.
你没事了  我在这里呢
You're all right. I'm here.
你能告诉我你是谁吗
Can you tell me who you are?
你能告诉我...
Can you tell me...
你的名字吗
your name?
我是谁
Who am I?
我的名字是什么
What is my name?
好啊
Yeah.
棒极了
Amazing.
我们加入他体内的八爪鱼DNA
The octopod DNA we introduced
起到了完全符合我预期的效果
provides exactly the effect I was looking for.
好好休息吧  孩子
Rest now, son.
我过一会儿就回来
I'll return momentarily
来告诉你你是谁
to tell you who you are.
我到底怎么了
What happened to me?
那是过去12个小时里
That's the seventh subject
你唤醒的第7个实验对象了
you've woken up in the past 12 hours.
我猜他和其他人一样
I assume he, like the others,
对自己先前的生活毫无印象了
has no memory of his previous life.
没错  也许重生所带来的创伤过重
Yes, perhaps the trauma of rebirth is simply too much
人类心智难以承受
for the human mind to process.
你一点都不担心
You're not worried.
我应该担心吗
Should I be?
教授  我们的雇主准备关闭我们的项目
Professor, our employers are going to shut us down.
你一定是知道的
You must know this.
我只知道我们所取得的成就
What I know is what we've accomplished.
我们令死人复生
We've woken the dead.
但是无一人能完好恢复记忆
And yet, none have returned with their memory intact.
那有什么
A tedious point.
我们能赋予他们设计好的  受我们支配的人格
What's more preferable than giving them personas
有比这更好的吗
that we design and control?
我们的雇主并不在乎这个
An argument lost on our employers,
他们只在乎一件事
who care about one thing and one thing only.
科学发现不是牛排
You cannot order scientific discoveries
不能预订  埃塞尔
the way you order a steak, Ethel.
接下来
Now...
我们来试试13号实验对象  如何
let's try Subject 13, shall we?
你怎么能这么做  布鲁斯少爷
How could you do this, Master Bruce?
我不是明确禁止你把那个女孩扯进来吗
I strictly forbid you from involving that little girl, didn't I?
我知道  但是塞琳娜总能自己应付麻烦
I know... but Selina's always handled herself.
我以为不会出事
I-I was sure.
但你错了  不是吗
But you were wrong, weren't you?
自己选择参与这种事另当别论
It's different if you choose to be involved in something like this,
但你主动把塞琳娜·凯尔扯了进来
but you actively involved Selina Kyle.
你把自己的事  放在了她的安危之前
You put your own concerns in front of that girl's safety.
你太过分了
You're way out of order.
你真令我大失所望  布鲁斯少爷
I'm... I'm really disappointed in you, Master Bruce.
你确定她还没逃出来吗
You're sure she's still there?
确定
Y-Yes.
不然我们约好了见面  她不会不来的
She wouldn't have missed our meeting otherwise.
斯特兰奇肯定是把她扣在了阿卡姆
Strange must be holding her prisoner in Arkham.
我怀疑她不是关在阿卡姆
Only I doubt she's in Arkham.
我敢说斯特兰奇把她关在了
I'll wager Strange has her in the
他造出阿泽瑞尔的秘密实验室里
secret lab where he created Azrael.
但斯特兰奇是阿卡姆的主管
But Strange runs Arkham.
他每天都在那里
He's seen there every day.
阿卡姆肯定是实验室的入口
The lab must be accessed through Arkham.
你认为是在地下
You're thinking it's underground.
一定是
It has to be.
肯定有楼梯  电梯
There must be stairs, an elevator,
通风井
ventilation shafts.
我只是不知道该怎么找
I just don't know how to find them.
我也许有办法
I may have a solution.
斯特兰奇用来制造这些怪物的技术
The technology Strange is using to create these monsters
肯定非常先进
must be very advanced.
我猜想  他在用钚同位素
My guess is, he's using plutonium isotopes
来变异细胞结构
to mutate cell structure.
如果是这样  一定会有微量辐射
If so, there'll be trace radiation.
我在韦恩集团
At Wayne Enterprises,
研发了一款用于战场的微型盖革计数器
I developed a miniature Geiger counter for battlefield use.
让我进入阿卡姆  我就能找到实验室的入口
Get me into Arkham and I'll find the entrance to that lab.
韦恩基金会每年都会捐钱给疯人院
Wayne Foundation gives the Asylum money every year.
我要求去参观一下
I'll ask for a tour.
去找那个派人刺杀你父亲的人吗
From the man that ordered the assassination of your father.
他会想知道我们了解多少
He'll want to find out what we know.
他不会把我和卢修斯当成威胁
And he won't see me and Lucius as a threat.
不
No.
绝对不行
Absolutely bloody not.
你不能就这么羊入虎口
You're not going to walk straight into a lion's den.
我腿这样都没法支援你
I can't even go to back you up with a leg like this, can I?
阿尔弗雷德  你自己也说
Alfred, you said yourself,
塞琳娜·凯尔出事都是我的错
that it's my fault what happened to Selina Kyle.
所以弥补是我的责任
That means it's my responsibility to make it right.
我或许不是你在街头斗殴中会选择的帮手
And I may not be the man you'd choose as second in a street fight,
但只要能保护布鲁斯  我都会尽力
but anything I can do to protect Bruce, I will.
但这计划还是不完整
Still, it's half a plan, isn't it?
就算卢修斯能把你带进去
I mean, just say that Lucius can get you in there,
你也找到了实验室的入口  然后呢
and you find the entrance to the laboratory, then what?
他们告诉我
They tell me.
我通知布洛克  他带一帮警察冲进去
I call Bullock, he comes busting in with a hundred cops,
让斯特兰奇忙不过来
keeps Strange busy.
我去找塞琳娜
I find Selina.
我知道了
I see.
那你究竟打算怎么进去呢
And how, exactly, do you plan on getting in?
他俩还有可能  但你...
I mean, these two possibly, but you...
斯特兰奇根本不会让你接近那里
I mean, Strange won't let you within a bloody mile of the place.
如果我能让你进大门
If I can get you inside the gate,
剩下的路你能自己解决吗
can you manage the rest of the way?
可以  我想我能
Yeah. I think I can.
乌贼是种有趣的生物
The cuttlefish is a fascinating creature.
可以再生脑细胞
Able to regenerate brain cells,
用皮肤分泌毒素
secrete toxins from its skin,
而且它们的基因还与人类很匹配
and its DNA meshes so well with human.
我等不及看它的效果了
I can't wait to see it in action.
把她皮质施加的电压增加一倍
Oh, I want to increase voltage to her cortex... 200%.
真的吗  先生
Are you certain, sir?
那相当于让她被闪电劈中
It'll be like she's being struck by a bolt of lightning.
我们还能造成什么伤害呢
Well, how much more damage could we possibly do?
她都死了
She's dead.
等你醒来我们再见  亲爱的
I'll see you when you wake, my dear.
很高兴你俩相处得这么好
I'm so pleased you two are getting along.
我警告你  尼格玛先生
I should warn you, Mr. Nygma,
斯特克先生是吃过人的
Mr. Stirk has been known to eat people.
但他已经保证不再吃了  是不是  斯特克先生
But he's promised to stop that, haven't you Mr. Stirk?
你得把我放出去
You have to get me out of here.
你是在求情吗
Are you asking for a favor?
你逃跑前应该考虑到这一点的
You should have considered that before you decided to escape.
你要怎么阻止吉姆·戈登
How are you going to stop Jim Gordon?
什么
What?
吉姆·戈登和哥谭市警局过去一周里
Jim Gordon and the GCPD have been here twice
已经来过两次了
in the last week.
他们显然是知道了
It's obvious that they know.
显然知道什么
Obvious they know what?
真要我说出来吗
Do I really have to say it?
你们在地下室制造怪物
You're making monsters in the basement!
我饿了
I'm hungry!
安静  斯特克
Quiet, Stirk.
地下室里有怪物
Monsters in the basement.
你真是疯了  尼格玛先生
You are insane, Mr. Nygma.
显然
Obviously.
吉姆·戈登就要来了
Jim Gordon is coming,
你们需要全部的帮助
and you're going to need all the help that you can get,
不如你去告诉斯特兰奇
so why don't you go tell Strange
如果他想阻止戈登和哥谭市警局
that if he wants to stop Gordon and the GCPD
就会需要我的帮助
then he's going to need my help.
马上去
Now!
有心跳了
We have a heartbeat.
她醒了  醒了
She's awake. She's awake.
赶紧  去叫斯特兰奇教授
Quickly, go get Professor Strange.
福克斯先生已经把车开到门口了
Mr. Fox is pulling up out front.
我跟戈登说  如果一小时内没你们的消息
I told Gordon if I don't hear from you within an hour,
我就去找布洛克
I'm going to go straight to Bullock.
我必须这么做  阿尔弗雷德
I have to do this, Alfred.
我没有选择
I don't have a choice.
你当然有选择
Of course you got a choice.
就像我可以选择祝福你  放你走
In the same way I can choose to let you go with my blessing
叫你把那小姑娘安全带回家
and tell you to bring that little girl home safe,
也可以现在就告诉你
or I can tell you right now,
我可以拽你上飞机
I can stick you on an airplane
送你去很远的地方
and fly you somewhere very far away.
-你不能  -别傻了  我当然可以
- You can't. - Don't be such a donker. Course I can.
但我不会那么做
But I won't.
这两年来  布鲁斯少爷
You see, for the past two years, Master Bruce,
我一直只想保护你  确保你的安全
all I've tried to do is protect you and keep you safe.
我以为那该是你父亲的心愿
Thinking that's what your father wanted.
但你已不是那个可怜的孤儿了  对不对
But you're not the same boy he left behind, are you?
所以我得问自己
So I have to ask myself...
如果托马斯·韦恩在这里  他会怎么做
what would Thomas Wayne do, if he were here?
你父亲为自己的行为负责
Your father took responsibility for his actions.
为了信念  他奋战到底
He fought very hard for what he believed in.
我不会阻止你做相同的事
And I will not stop you from doing the same thing.
所以
So...
去吧
off you go.
戈登和福克斯先生在等你呢
Gordon and Mr. Fox be waiting for you.
欢迎回到这世上  亲爱的
Welcome back to the world, my dear.
我猜  你肯定觉得挺...
I imagine you're feeling rather...
困惑
confused.
能告诉我  你是谁吗
Can you tell me who you are?
记得你的名字吗
Do you remember your name?
有任何记忆吗
Anything?
你是个女战神
You are a war goddess.
你叫安卓斯特
Your name is Andraste.
不
No.
不吗
No?
我叫菲什·穆尼
My name is Fish Mooney.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你能再重复一遍吗
Could you please repeat that?
我说  我叫菲什·穆尼  贱人
I said, my name is Fish Mooney, bitch.
你最好告诉我
And you better tell me
这到底是怎么回事
what the hell is going on.
你把我关在这里是个错误
You're making a mistake keeping me locked in here.
你听到了吗
Do you hear me?
是什么让她复生后记忆完好呢
What allowed her to come back with her memories intact?
目前还不好说
It's too soon to tell.
也许跟电压增高有关
Perhaps it was the increased voltage.
与她自身DNA拼接的那条乌贼DNA
Something unique about the cuttlefish DNA
有什么特别之处
we spliced with her own.
还有  她是从那条脏河里捞出来的
And then again, she was pulled from that filthy river.
也许是水里的污染物
Perhaps a contaminant from the water
改变了这一过程
altered the process.
初步检查显示她的脑功能
Early readings have detected abnormalities
有些异常
in her brain functions.
对
Yes.
她可能会显现出能力
She may reveal abilities.
最重要的是她知道自己的身份
The most important thing is that she knows who she is.
我们的主人会很满意
Our masters will be pleased.
我们创造了第一个真正的"复活者"
We've created the first true reanimant.
你考虑好尼格玛先生的提议了吗
Have you made a decision about Mr. Nygma's offer?
是啊  让他试试吧  好吗
Oh, yes. Let's let him have a go, shall we?
他机智地找到了地下室
He was clever enough to find his way to the basement,
也确实说得有理
and he does have a point.
他了解吉姆·戈登
He knows Jim Gordon.
我会告诉他的
I'll tell him.
布鲁斯·韦恩在大门前找你
Bruce Wayne is at the front gate asking for you,
还带了个韦恩集团的人
and he has someone from Wayne Enterprises with him.
这招真大胆
Bold move.
这小孩越来越让我佩服了
I'm more and more impressed with this boy.
要告诉他你不在吗
Shall I tell him you're not here?
相反
On the contrary.
我很想跟他谈谈
I very much want to speak with him.
放行
Releasing.
雨果·斯特兰奇  乐意为你效劳
Hugo Strange, at your service.
-卢修斯·福克斯  -福克斯先生
- Lucius Fox. - Mr. Fox.
当然  你是
And of course, you are...
布鲁斯·韦恩
Bruce Wayne.
终于见到你  我深感荣幸
I can't tell you what it means to finally meet you.
你父亲是我的好友
Your father was very dear to me.
他和你母亲的遭遇
What happened to him and your mother,
真是一场悲剧
was indeed a great tragedy.
请接受我迟到的哀悼
Please accept my condolences, belated as they may be.
谢谢
Thank you.
有什么需要我帮助的吗
So how can I be of help?
不用说
It goes without saying
没有韦恩集团的大力支持
that the work we do here would not be possible
我们的工作就根本无法开展
without the support of the Wayne Foundation.
我父母生前非常关心疯人院的改造
The asylum was a cause close to my parents' hearts.
所以  我认为我应该
As such, I believe it is my duty
来看看他们的钱都花在了哪
to see how their money is being spent.
所以这算是来视察吗
So this is a bit of an inspection?
没那么正式
Oh, nothing so formal.
我们只是想四处看看
We were just hoping for a look around.
我们一般不允许参观
We don't normally give tours.
提供了你们四分之一经营预算的人也不行吗
Even to someone who provides a quarter of your operating budget?
我们当然可以破例
Of course, we can make exceptions.
我乐意为你带路
I'd be happy to be your guide.
事实上  我想和你好好谈谈
Actually, I thought that you and I could talk,
让福克斯先生四处看看
while Mr. Fox looks around.
他比较仔细
He's very discreet.
我知道了
I see.
你这是有备而来
You've come armed with a plan.
恐怕不能允许
I'm afraid we can't allow
平民四处乱转
civilians to wander about,
但也许我的助手
but perhaps my assistant,
皮博迪女士能够陪同福克斯先生
Ms. Peabody, could accompany Mr. Fox.
好的  我去拿我的外套
That's fine. I'll just get my coat.
韦恩先生  请
Mr. Wayne... if you will.
布鲁斯跟斯特兰奇去他办公室了
Bruce is going with Strange to his office,
我能四处转转
while I get the tour.
我有什么发现就用这个标记出来
I see anything... I'll mark it with this.
你可以出来了
You're clear.
这过期了
This is expired.
是啊  我把新的弄丢了
Yeah, I lost my new one.
一直想去补办来着
Keep meaning to have it replaced.
今天就去补
Do it today.
这是我们的休闲室
This is our rec room,
我们的犯人能在这里练习社交技巧
where our inmates work on their socialization skills.
这制服是谁设计的
Who, um, designed the uniforms?
你在心理健康方面有所涉猎吗  福克斯先生
Do you have much training in mental health, Mr. Fox?
不  完全没有
None. None at all.
我们继续吧
Shall we continue?
布鲁斯  虽然我非常高兴终于见到了你
Bruce, as much as I value the opportunity to finally meet you,
但也许我们该挑明你来访的真实目的了吧
perhaps we could address the real reason for your visit.
我不知道你在说什么
I'm not sure I know what you mean.
前两天  詹姆斯·戈登来见我
Well, you see, the other day, James Gordon came to see me.
他问起了我和你父亲十年前合作过的
He asked about a project that your father and I worked on
一个项目
a decade ago.
据他说  是你授意他进行调查的
I was led to believe that he was acting on your behalf.
你不就是为此而来吗
Is that not why you're here?
他离开哥谭市警局后
After he left the GCPD,
我雇戈登先生调查我父母的死
I retained Mr. Gordon to look into my parents' deaths.
他在追查好几条线索
He's been pursuing various leads,
他并不事事都向我汇报
and he doesn't share everything with me.
如果他有逾越  或冒犯了你
If he overstepped or caused some offense,
我很抱歉
you have my apologies.
谢谢
Thank you.
我能理解你想得到答案
And I can understand how you want answers.
你肯定很难接受
How difficult it must be to accept
那样一件可怕的事
that something so horrific
自己父母的被杀
as the murder of one's own parents,
会是随机  毫无道理的
could be a random and meaningless act.
所以你想讨个说法
So you want a reason.
找人怪罪
Someone to blame.
就他们的事而言  我觉得是有罪人
In their case, I think there was someone to blame.
我也这么认为
Oh, so do I.
加糖吗
Sugar?
阿卡姆疯人院在
Arkham Asylum has been open
使用水疗和穿孔的年代之前
before the days of water cures
就建立了
and trepanning.
穿孔是指在颅骨上钻孔释放坏体液
That's boring a hole in the skull to release bad humors.
我们现在已经不那么做了
We don't do that anymore.
那是什么
What is that?
是个空气质量测量计
Oh, this measures air quality.
检测微粒
Micro particles.
韦恩先生担心病人们所处环境是否健康
Mr. Wayne is concerned that the patients are in a healthy environment.
担心哮喘隐患什么的
Asthma and whatnot.
目前看来情况还不错
You're doing good so far.
那太好了
I'm so relieved.
这边走
This way.
福克斯先生
Mr. Fox?
嗯
Yep.
来了
Coming.
你很像他
You remind me of him.
托马斯
Thomas.
你们有一样的眼神
You have that same look in your eyes.
什么眼神
What look is that?
坚定
Certainty.
作为科学家  这是我无法拥有的奢侈
As a scientist, that's a luxury that I cannot afford.
在科学中  总得保持一定的怀疑
No, in science, there must always be some doubt,
但托马斯没有
but not with Thomas, no.
托马斯对事物抱有信念
Thomas believed in things.
我觉得你是指
I think what you're referring to is...
道德准则
moral principles.
是的
Yes.
可惜  科学和道德相处并不融洽
Sadly, science and moral absolutes do not make easy bedfellows.
我们以前起的那些争执啊
Oh, the arguments we used to have.
我永远劝不动他
I could never make him listen.
我很高兴
I'm glad to hear that.
是吗
Are you?
你有没有想过  如果你父亲不那么坚定
Haven't you ever imagined a life that might have been,
生活可能是怎样一番模样
if your father hadn't been so certain?
如果他听了劝的话
If he had listened?
那他就不是他了
Then he wouldn't have been the man he was.
是啊
True.
但他也不会死了
But he wouldn't be dead, either.
还有你母亲
Along with your mother.
你父亲珍视的那些理想  真值得吗
Are those ideals that your father cherished so worth it?
你难道不想拿你坚信的一切
Wouldn't you gladly trade everything you believe
来换哪怕一天
for one more day,
一小时
one more hour,
你父母活过来吗
with your parents alive?
那么你承认了
So you admit it, then.
你承认你做了什么
You admit what you did.
我承认的是  布鲁斯
Here's what I admit, Bruce.
我曾是你父亲的朋友
That I was your father's friend.
我恳请过他
That I pleaded with him,
如今我也恳请你
as I plead with you now:
回去吧
Turn back.
你肯定有在乎的人
Surely you have those that you care about.
为了他们  为了你自己
For their sake, as well as your own,
做出你父亲没做的选择吧
make the choice your father did not.
你一直在找杀害你父母的凶手
You have been searching for the man who killed your parents,
但答案其实一直近在眼前
but the answer has always been right in front of you.
布鲁斯  你父亲让你变成了孤儿
Bruce, your father orphaned you.
是他的行动招致了那枚杀死他
His actions fired the bullet that killed him,
和你母亲的子弹
and your mother.
他清楚自己在做什么  还是一往直前
He knew what he was doing, and he did it anyway.
我求你  不要追随他走的道路
I'm begging you not to follow his path.
你问我  我是不是希望我父母还活着
You want to know if I wish my parents were alive?
当然
Of course.
我愿不愿付出一切换他们回来
Would I give anything to have them back?
当然
Yes.
但我父亲为他的信念
But my father fought and died
抗争  牺牲
for what he believed was right.
如果有必要
And if necessary...
我也会的
...so will I.
抓住他们
Take them.
看来你真是有其父必有其子
It seems you are your father's son.
我要你知道我多么敬重这一点
I want you to know how greatly I respect that.
塞琳娜·凯尔在哪
Where's Selina Kyle?
你把她怎么了
What have you done with her?
他们把你锁得好严实
They got you locked up good in here.
我会把我们弄出去的  布莉姬特
I'm going to get us out of here, Bridgit.
布鲁斯会找到我们的
Bruce is going to find us and...
然后我们找人给你看看
we'll get you help.
吃午饭了
Lunchtime.
我在哪
Where am I?
这不是一座岛吧
This isn't an island, is it?
女士  我只是个打工的
Hey, lady, I just work here.
要不要吃午饭了
You want your lunch?
你想干点有用的事吗
You want to make yourself useful?
给我做个烤奶酪三明治
Make me a grilled cheese sandwich.
会有人来找那韦恩家的孩子的
Someone will come looking for the Wayne boy.
是啊
Yes.
你喜欢他
You like him.
他很像托马斯
He reminds me of Thomas,
而我怀念他
whom I miss,
虽然这看上去很讽刺
ironic as that might seem.
那孩子是个威胁
The boy is a threat.
你知道该做什么
You know what needs to be done.
你没多少时间了
You don't have much time.
你的时间比你想的还要少
You have less than you imagine.
糟糕
Oh, no.
我们得谈谈  斯特兰奇
We need a word, Strange.
当然  我要怎么帮您
Of course. How might I be of service?
首先是父亲  现在是儿子
First the father, now the son.
你总是能吸引韦恩家族的目光
You have a habit of catching the eye of the Wayne family.
一切都在控制之中
Everything is under control.
你是这么说
So you say.
事实上  你已经忘记你的任务了
The fact is, you've lost sight of your mission.
派人拿着剑跑去哥谭
Sending men with swords into Gotham.
还有拿着冷冻枪的怪物
Freaks armed with freeze guns.
我的确有些失误
There have been missteps, I grant you,
但看看我们的成就啊
but look at all we've accomplished.
我才不在乎你的怪物呢
I do not care about your monsters.
他们跟起死回生有什么关系
What do they have to do with restoring the dead to life?
肢体再生一直是起死回生的
Physical regenereration has always been a necessary part
重要部分
of bringing back the dead.
我不得不采取一切必要手段
I had to resort to any means necessary
让人更强壮  更敏捷
to make humans stronger, faster...
虽说如此
Be that as it may,
你的主目标失败了
you have failed at your core objective.
不是这样的
That is not true.
永生是要起死回生
Immortality means returning to life
同时完好保存心智和记忆
with one's mind and memories intact,
而你没能做到
and you have not.
我做到了
Oh, but I have.
-什么时候  -今天
- When? - Today.
我把一个人复活了
I brought someone back.
记忆  情绪  灵魂
Memories, emotion, the soul itself,
全部起死回生
back from death.
如果你在撒谎
If you're lying...
我没有
I am not.
你能重复这一过程吗
Can you repeat the process?
再给我点时间
If given time,
我想可以的
I believe so.
好吧
Very well.
查明韦恩家的孩子
Find out what the Wayne boy
和他的同伴都知道什么
and his companions know.
尽可能将一切都转移到州北的设施去
Move everything you can to the facility upstate.
然后毁掉一切印第安山的证据
Then destroy any evidence of Indian Hill.
毁掉是指
By destroy, you mean...
你有爆炸装置
You have an explosive device.
好好使用
Use it.
毁掉印第安山
Destroy Indian Hill.
这是什么
What's this?
烤奶酪三明治
It's a grilled cheese sandwich.
你给我做了个三明治
You made me a sandwich?
是的
Yeah.
为什么
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
你叫我做了
You told me to.
等等
Wait.
我不知道该怎么办  布莉姬特
I don't know what to do, Bridgit.
很简单
It's simple.
你可以死
You can die.
放下
Drop it.
别逼我伤害你
Don't make me hurt you.
你觉得你伤得了我
You think you can hurt me?
我可是火之女神
I am the Goddess of Fire.
你才不是什么女神
You're not the goddess of anything.
你是布莉姬特
You're Bridgit.
我们是一起长大的
We grew up together.
我们是朋友  我母亲离开后
We're friends. When my mom left,
是你收留了我
you took me in.
女神才没有朋友
Goddesses don't have friends.
-谁说的  -教授
- Says who? - The Professor.
他告诉我我是谁了
He told me who I am.
去他的
Screw him.
记得鸽子吗
Remember the pigeons?
我们以前常去喂他们
How we used to feed them?
是我啊  塞琳娜
It's me, Selina. You...
你肯定记得的
You've got to remember.
我
I...
凯尔烧得很旺  但乔烧得最亮
Cale flamed up good, but Joe burned the brightest.
好吧  嗯  对
Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
你烧死了你的哥哥
You fried your brothers.
虽然我期待的不是这段记忆  不过也算是记忆了
Not the memory I was hoping for, but it's something.
你会烧得很亮的
You'll burn bright.
我确定
I know it.
不  不
No. No.
我是萤火虫
I am Firefly.
火奈何不了我
Fire cannot touch me.
糟糕
Oh, crap.
你是火之女神  是吧
You're the Goddess of Fire, right?
是吧
Right?
女神都有仆人的
Goddesses have servants and stuff.
让我做你的仆人吧
Let me be your servant.
我为什么需要仆人
Why do I need a servant?
没有仆人就不算女神
You can't be a goddess without a servant.
这是故事里讲的啊
Come on, it's totally part of the story.
教授肯定是忘记说了
The Professor just forgot to tell you.
你必须有个仆人
You've got to have a servant.
看来是真的
I guess that's true.
当然
Hello.
天呐
Oh, man.
除非我另下令  全部值双班
Double shifts until I say otherwise,
所有警员上街巡逻
and I want everyone in a uniform out on the streets.
布洛克
Bullock.
戈登  布鲁斯少爷和福克斯都还在阿卡姆
Gordon, Master Bruce and Fox are still in Arkham.
他们这会儿该出来了  肯定是有麻烦了
They should be out by now. They're in trouble.
那个混蛋
That son of a bitch!
吉姆·戈登
Jim Gordon,
他在逼我啊
I mean, he's forcing my hand.
你听到了吗
Are you listening to me?
拿上你的枪和警徽
Grab your gun, your badge,
还有什么的  我们赶紧走
and your bits and your bobs, and let's go.
稍等一下
Hold on a second, okay?
那里可建得跟堡垒一样
You're talking about a place that's built like a fortress.
到处是持枪警卫
Chockablock with armed guards.
虽然我们可以派
Now, while we could send in an assault force
中年爱尔兰矮挫警探
of a pudgy, middle-aged Irish detective
和一个才受过刀伤的英国人去
and a recently stabbed Englishman,
但哥谭市警局的代理警监
I think the acting captain of the GCPD
可以做到更好
could do a little better.
好了  去救我们的哥们
Right, go get our guys.
B队  跟我
Bravo team, on me.
卢修斯
Lucius.
布鲁斯  你没事吧
Bruce, are you okay?
我没事  戈登呢
I'm fine. Where's Gordon?
我没见到他
I haven't seen him.
抱歉我害你卷了进来  卢修斯
I'm sorry I got you into this, Lucius.
看来我们都要死在这里了
It seems likely we're all going to die in here.
别那么说
Don't say that.
我不介意死
I don't mind dying.
我介意我害你  吉姆·戈登
I mind that I got you and Jim Gordon
还有塞琳娜·凯尔都卷了进来
and Selina Kyle involved.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
你是个了不起的年轻人
You are a remarkable young man,
但你没逼我们任何人做什么
but you didn't force any of us to do anything.
这是我们的选择
We chose.
雨果·斯特兰奇说这么久以来
Hugo Strange said that all this time
我一直在找杀害我父母的凶手
I've been searching for the man who killed my parents...
其实就是我父亲
...when really it was my own father.
说他很清楚自己在做什么
That he knew what he was doing.
还说我有其父必有其子
That I am my father's son.
布鲁斯  你父亲有勇气为
Bruce, your father had the courage to fight
自己的信念而斗争
for what he believed in.
只要有生命  就有希望
And as long as there's life, there's hope.
真感人
Touching sentiment.
你是谁  吉姆·戈登在哪
Who are you? Where's Jim Gordon?
我建议你们还是担心自己吧
I would urge you to worry about yourselves right now.
吉姆·戈登自己另有麻烦呢
Jim Gordon has his own problems.
斯特兰奇  你个混蛋
Strange, you son of a bitch!
布鲁斯·韦恩呢  你敢伤害他
Where's Bruce Wayne? If you've hurt him...
布鲁斯·韦恩还活着
Bruce Wayne is alive.
暂时而已
For now.
你敢激我
Try me,
他可能就活不下去了
and that may change.
你别想逃脱罪责
You won't get away with this.
有人知道我们在这儿
People know we're here.
他们已经前来阻止你了
They're already on their way to stop you.
是啊  恐怕我不能允许他们那么做
Yes, and I'm afraid I simply can't allow that.
我的工作太重要了
The work that I'm doing here is too important
现在又是太关键的关头
and at too critical a juncture,
幸运的是
but fortunately
已经出现了一个解决办法
a solution has presented itself.
先生们
Gentlemen.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
别动
Hold still.
这溶液很重要
The solution is very important.
可别弄洒了一滴
You mustn't spill a drop.
情况就是这样
So here's the situation.
斯特兰奇教授叫我来查明
Professor Strange has tasked me with finding out
你们俩对他的作为究竟了解多少
how much you two know about what he's been up to
更重要的是  你们还告诉了谁
and, more importantly, who you told.
带我们去见吉姆·戈登和塞琳娜·凯尔
Show us Jim Gordon and Selina Kyle.
你应该是没太明白现在谁说了算
Think you're not quite grasping the power dynamic here,
小高领
Turtleneck.
我刚刚说到
As I was saying...
我们需要知道你们知道什么
we need to know what you know,
你们得告诉我
and you're going to tell me,
否则你们头上的喷头就会喷下毒气
or poison gas will spew from the nozzles above your head
你们两个都会死得
and you will both die very...
非常痛苦
very painfully.
我认得这声音
I know this voice.
他原来是哥谭市警局的人
He worked for the GCPD.
有个挺奇怪的名字
He had a funny kind of name.
我的名字没什么奇怪的
There's nothing funny about my name.
他就是陷害了吉姆·戈登的那个
He was the one that framed Jim Gordon.
你一直是个聪明人  福小斯
You always were a smart cookie, Foxy.
知道斯特兰奇为什么叫我干这个吗
You know why Strange gave me this job?
因为他知道
It's because he knows
我会毫不犹豫地杀了你俩
that I would kill you both and not bat an eye.
记住这一点
So, keeping that in mind...
给你们五分钟
...five minutes on the clock.
开始计时
Starting... now.
有趣
Fun.
那是干什么
What the hell was that?
你会知道的
You'll see.
容我介绍巴兹尔
Allow me to introduce Basil.
巴兹尔今早才醒来
Basil just woke up this morning.
是吧  孩子
Didn't you, son?
是啊
Yep.
他很糊涂  小可怜
He was so confused, poor soul.
他忘记了自己的身份
He had forgotten who he was
直到我让他记起了他的天赋
until I reminded him of his great talent.
巴兹尔是位天赋异禀的表演者
You see, Basil is a gifted performer.
可以说是变色龙
A chameleon of sorts.
想见识一下吗
Would you like to see?
你也该进疯人院  斯特兰奇
You belong in your own asylum, Strange.
你  吉姆·戈登  该留在过去
And you, James Gordon, belong in the past.
世界已经向前进了
The world has moved on.
你和其他你这样的人
While you and others like you
还过着悲哀正常的生活时
were living your sad, normal lives,
我则在推动革命的界限
I was pushing the boundaries of evolution.
未来属于我的孩子们
The future belongs to my children
那个未来已经到来
and that future is here.
前往阿卡姆疯人院
Inbound to Arkham Asylum.
突击队已就绪
Strike force ready.
告诉我你们知道什么
Just tell me what you know.
令人震惊
Astonishing.
是啊  是啊
Oh, yes, oh, yes.
还有最后的一点
The finishing touch.
介绍下自己  孩子
Introduce yourself, son.
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
我是吉姆·戈登
I'm Jim Gordon.